# **Vadim Halian**

FRONT END DEVELOPER (5 YEARS)

### **Details**

Chisinau

Moldova

+37360902743

vadym.h.dev@gmail.com

### Links

github

linkedIn

telegram

### **Skills**

JavaScript

React

**HTML** 

**CSS** 

### Languages

**English - Upper Intermediate** 

Ukrainian - Native

# **Summary**

Motivated and skilled software engineer with more than 5 years of experience specializing in **React**, **Redux and Typescript**.

Experienced in starting projects from scratch and configuring webpack, linters, testing environments, pipelines etc. Experienced in developing a scalable and maintainable architecture.

# **Employment History**

### Tech Lead Frontend Developer, Alar, Budva

February 2022 - Present

- Configured project from scratch (webpack, linters, CI/CD).
- Developed architecture patterns, which significantly reduced onboarding time of new team members.
- Revamped cross-code review procedures to substantially boost speed and efficiency, elevating the overall review process.
- Implemented an alternative method of building dev server with Vite, reducing compiling time by 10 times.
- Ensured proper documentation of the code, making it easy for team members to understand and contribute.

### Senior Frontend Developer, Alar, Budva

January 2021 - February 2022

- Identified and optimized frontend performance bottlenecks to enhance the speed and efficiency of web applications.
- Ensured that web applications comply with accessibility standards, making them usable for people with disabilities.
- Actively participated in project planning meetings and provided technical insights to facilitate effective decision-making.
- Implemented new features based on project requirements, ensuring timely delivery and alignment with established coding standards.

## Frontend Developer Digicode, Kyiv

January 2019 - January 2021

- Identified and resolved front-end bugs, UI glitches and performance issues.
- Collaborated with the team to implement new features based on project requirements.
- Participated in code reviews, provided constructive feedback.
- Ran tests and ensured cross-browser support.
- Used Axios library to fetch data from server, serialized and rendered it.

# **Education**

Bachelor Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Kyiv

September 2014 - July 2018